# Douglas C. Wu

Bioinformatics Scientist/Engineer

+1-310-658-1540
in /wckdouglas

• @wckdouglas

♥ wckdouglas.github.io♥ wckdouglas➡ wckdouglas@gmail.com

## **O** Professional summary

Highly-motivated fast learner with > 8 years of bioinformatics consultation, engineer and research experiences. Collaborative and innovative with strong communication and interpersonal abilities. Staying up-to-date with industrial trends in sequencing and bioinformatics technologies. Comfortable with working in a fast-paced environment.

## **⇔** Skills

**Bioinformatics** Variant Calling, Multiplex PCR primer design, WGS-seq, Targeted DNA-seq, RNA-seq, 16S-seq, methyl-seq, experimental design, familiar with public \*-omics databases and their APIs, such as UCSC and Ensembl

**Coding** Python, R, Bash, Rust, SQL, C/C++, Matlab

**Computing** Familiar with Amazon Web Service (AWS), High performance computing (SGE and SLURM), Snowflake, Docker/Singularity, GitHub Action, Jenkins

**Deep learning framework** JAX/STAX, PyTorch, Keras/Tensorflow

**Experimental skills** Cell-free DNA and RNA-seq, Methyl-seq, Molecular diagostics, Live cell imaging

## **Experience**

Invitae January 2021 – Present

Bioinformatics Engineer/Scientist

Rockville, MD

- > Collaborated with R&D scientist to develop, optimize and validate novel experimental (Illumina and Pacbio) and computational methods for high-throughput detection of germline mutations (SNV, InDels, repeat expansions) in "hard-to-do" genes
- > Integrated validated R&D tools into production pipeline python codebase to expand current clinical genetic testing offerings for pharmaceutical partners to increase revenue by 80% per sample
- > Developed RESTful endpoints to stream data for clinical geneticist data review and enable LIMS automation to support processing of >1,000 samples/month
- > Established assay development process for integration testings across different production systems
- > Developed R&D code to interact with different internal microservices to decrease turnover time in genomics experiments
- > Performed code review to improve code quality of the production pipeline and led collaborative efforts to refactor production code base to warrant genetic testing accuracy

QIAGEN

July 2019 – December 2020

Bioinformatics Scientist

Frederick, MD

- > Provided bioinformatics consultation for thousands to million-dollar-sized NGS projects from experimental design to result reporting
- > Expert in data visualization and progress/result reporting presentations for academic, pharmaceutical and biotech researcher customers, and internal stakeholders
- > Worked with global product managers to establish genomics services cost calculations to provide more competitive service pricing

## **Education**

#### **Univeristy of Texas at Austin**

Ph.D in Molecular Genetics specialized in Bioinformatics

University of Illinois at Urbana Champaign

BS in Biochemistry

Austin, TX 2009 – 2013 Champaign, IL

2013 - 2019